Register of the Milly Bennett papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1917-circa 1956 (Boxes 6-14)
  - Articles and manuscripts
    - Processed articles from Valencia, Spain, 1937 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Radio interview with Milly Bennett on Chronicle "Feature Edition" program, 1938 March 18 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Draft, notes on radio interview conducted by Milly Bennett with her husband, Hans Amlie, KSRO, Santa Rosa, California, 1938 July 1
    - "Write a Book?," Scoop, the magazine of the Press Club of San Francisco, 1938 August (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - "A Bouquet for the Bride" (carbon copy), circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - "Camp Follower - 1944 Style" (draft), circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - "The Dog Collar" (draft), circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - "The Friendship Quilt" (draft), circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - "How To Lose a Ration" (draft), circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - "I Almost Lost My Head" (carbon copy), circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes, circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - Untitled, incomplete manuscript on Milly Bennett's experiences in China (first draft?), circa 1950
      - Synopsis (Box-folder 10: 10)
      - Chapter 2 (Box-folder 10: 11)
      - Chapter 3 (Box-folder 10: 12)
      - Chapters 10-16 (Box-folder 10: 13)
      - Chapters 17-21 (Box-folder 10: 14)
      - Chapters 22-26 (Box-folder 10: 15)
    - Untitled, incomplete manuscript on Milly Bennett's experiences in China (second draft?), circa 1950
      - Chapters 1-5 (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - Chapters 6-9 (Box-folder 11: 2)
      - Chapters 16-17 (Box-folder 11: 3)
      - Chapters 18-19 (Box-folder 11: 4)
      - Chapters 20-22 (Box-folder 11: 5)
      - Chapters 23-26 (Box-folder 11: 6)
      - Miscellaneous notes, parts of chapters (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Autobiography (first draft?), circa 1956
      - Prologue (Box-folder 12: 1)
      - Chapter 1 (Box-folder 12: 2)
      - Chapter 2 (Box-folder 12: 3)
      - Chapter 3 (Box-folder 12: 4)
      - Chapter 4 (Box-folder 12: 5)
      - Chapters 5-8 (Box-folder 12: 6)
      - Chapter entitled "The End of Book" (Box-folder 12: 7)
      - Notes, parts of chapters (Box-folder 12: 8)
      - Draft, typescript with holograph notes (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - "The Girl With the Whistling Eye" autobiography, incomplete (second draft?), circa 1956
      - Chapters 2-3 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - Chapters 5-8 (Box-folder 13: 2)
      - Chapters 9-12 (Box-folder 13: 3)
      - Chapters 13-17 (Box-folder 13: 4)
      - Chapters 18-22 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      - Chapters 23-26 (Box-folder 13: 6)
      - Chapters 28-30 (Box-folder 13: 7)
      - Chapters 31, 32, 35, 36, miscellaneous notes (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - "The Girl With the Whistling Eye" autobiography (third draft?), circa 1956
      - Chapters 1-5 (Box-folder 14: 1)
      - Chapters 6-10 (Box-folder 14: 2)
      - Chapters 11-15 (Box-folder 14: 3)
      - Chapters 16-20 (Box-folder 14: 4)
      - Chapters 21-25 (Box-folder 14: 5)
      - Chapters 26-29 (Box-folder 14: 6)
      - Chapters 30-33 (Box-folder 14: 7)
      - Chapters 34-36, postlude (Box-folder 14: 8)
- COLLECTED WRITINGS, 1917-circa 1941 (Box 15)
  Writings of other authors, including typescript, holograph, and autographed manuscripts, arranged alphabetically by name of writer.
  - Amlie, Hans (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - "Friends of Humanity - Friends of Democracy"
    - "I Still Have Mine"
    - "Story of Hans Amlie" related to Leland Stowe
    - "War in Spain" (a talk by Amlie to migrant workers)
    - "War Without Love" (2 copies)
  - Bland, Henry Meade (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - "Mount Davidson Park"
    - "To John McLaren"
  - Daily News staff, San Francisco - Drawings, verses, notes, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Hawkins, Ann - Letters about Spain (planned for publication), 1938 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Mitchell, Mike (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Untitled
    - "Autotell of One W. K. 'Doc' Adams"
    - "Between Editions" - verses
    - "California Chronicles, or Life in the Far West"
    - "Dayton Days"
    - "Leomele Hawaii"
    - "Mitchell Tells All; Not Hit by Crutch"
    - "Searching"
    - "Song from the Chinese"
    - "When I Was in the Army"
  - Prohme, William - "Rayna Simons Prohme, A Report on the Last Months of Her Life" (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Spender, Stephen - "Hitch-hiking in Republican Spain" (holograph) (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Sterling, George - "The Revenge" (poem) (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (manuscript on the Spanish Civil War, may not have been published) (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Chapter I - "Why They Went"
    - Chapter II - "Where They Are"
    - Chapter III - "Training Camp - A Bit of America"
    - Chapter IV - "Battles at Jarama"
    - Chapter V - "American Base Hospital"
    - Chapter VI - "July Offensive - Madrid"
    - Chapter VII - "Wounded Men"
    - Chapter VIII - "The Taking of Villa Nueva de la Canada"
    - Chapter X - "Harder Days"
- SUBJECT FILE, 1921-1942 (Boxes 16-19)
  Reports, printed matter, and press releases, arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
  - Asia, 1927 April, May (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - California
    - The Coast, 1938 July, August, October (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Sunset, 1928 June (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - China
    - Miscellany - Cartoon, calling cards, emblems, circa 1927 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 16: 5)
      - Hankow Herald, 1927 July 19
      - North China Standard, 1926 March 26
      - The Peking Leader (clipping), 1927 March 26
      - The People's Tribune, 1926 November 7
  - Council of Jamaica Farm Workers' Welfare Association (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Daily News San Francisco (advertisement) (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Hawaii - Printed matter (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Harding, President Warren G. - Galley of front page of The Honolulu Advertiser on the death of Harding, 1923 August 2 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Health - Moray radiant energy device (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Miscellany
    - General (Box-folder 16: 11)
    - Printed matter
      - Undated (Box-folder 16: 12)
      - 1921 (Box-folder 16: 13)
      - 1925 (Box-folder 16: 14)
      - 1928 (Box-folder 16: 15)
      - 1929 (Box-folder 16: 16)
      - 1930 (Box-folder 16: 17)
      - 1933 (Box-folder 16: 18)
      - 1935 (Box-folder 16: 19)
      - 1936 (Box-folder 16: 20)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 16: 21)
      - 1939 (Box-folder 16: 22)
      - 1940-1942 (Box-folder 16: 23)
  - Moscow Daily News, 1931 March 28, April 2, May 24; 1936 November 3 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Outer Mongolia - "The Truth About Outer Mongolia" by Edward Dunn, 1935 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Spain
    - Civil War
      - Amlie, Thomas - Letter and newsletter by Thomas Amlie (Box-folder 17: 3)
      - British Royal Air Force - Report by Wing Commander Gade and Captain Pearson on Republican Spain, 1938 February (Box-folder 17: 4)
      - International Brigade (Box-folder 17: 5)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 17: 6)
      - News of Spain (incomplete), 1938 February - 1939 February (Box-folder 17: 7)
      - Poetry (Box-folder 17: 8)
      - Press releases, 1937
        - February-April (Box-folder 17: 9)
        - May-June (Box-folder 17: 10)
        - July-September (Box-folder 18: 1)
      - Printed matter
        - Undated (Box-folder 18: 2)
        - 1937 (Box-folder 18: 3)
        - 1938 (Box-folder 18: 4-5)
        - 1939 (Box-folder 18: 6)
      - Valencia
        - Map (Box-folder 18: 7)
        - Press bulletins (Box-folder 18: 8)
          - Excerpts from the speech of Largo Caballero, President of the Council of Ministers, at the Cortes in Valencia, 1937 February 1
          - Information bulletin, 1937 October 3, 14, 21
    - Communist Party (Box-folder 18: 9)
      - "An Open Letter from the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of Spain to the Executive Commission of the Spanish Socialist Workers' Party Making an Official and Concrete Proposal of Unification"
      - Report of Jose Diaz, General Secretary of the Communist Party of Spain, at the Plenum of the Central Committee of the Communist Party held in Valencia, 1937 November
    - Printed matter
      - 1935 (Box-folder 18: 10)
      - 1940 (Box-folder 18: 11)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - U.S.S.R.
    - Children's book, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - List of foreign correspondents (in Russian) (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Karelia (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Maps (Box-folder 19: 4)
      - Caucasus-Crimea
      - Kharkov
      - Kiev
      - Minsk
      - Moscow
      - Odessa
      - Soviet Union
      - Stalingrad
    - Moscow Trial, 1936 (Box-folder 19: 5)
      Indictment, testimony (incomplete), summary of evidence of the Zinovieites: G. E. Zinoviev, L. B. Kamenev, G. E. Yevdokimov, I. N. Smirnov, I. P. Bakavev, V. A. Ter-Vaganyan, S. V. Mrachkovski, A. E. Dreitser, E. S. Hatsman, I. I. Reingold, R. V. Pikel, V. P. Olberg, K. B. Berman-Yurin, Fritz David (I. I. Kruglyanski), M. Lourier, and N. Lourier.
    - Music, including a booklet of Red Army songs (in Russian) (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Translations from the Soviet Press - Typescripts, carbons, holographs, 1936 (Box-folder 19: 7-11)
  - United Federal Workers of America - Constitution (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - United States Department of Agriculture - Farm Security Administration - Migrant camps (newsletters, notes, correspondence, printed matter), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - United States Department of Justice - Alien registration form (Box-folder 19: 14)
- PRINTED MATTER (Box 20)
  Originals of newspaper articles by and about Milly Bennett, photocopies of which are filed in the collection.
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Photo file)
  503 prints / 5 albums / 32 negatives / 186 post cards
  - 5 photograph albums, 1920-1939 (Album fA)
    1 album of childhood photographs; 1 album in Hawaii, circa 1920; 1 album in Hawaii, 1922-1925; 1 album in China, 1926-1927; 1 album in Spain, 1936-1937 (contains clippings, 1938-1939).
  - 18 prints of unidentified people in Hawaii; 5 prints, 1 negative of Professor Hermann J. Muller (Envelope B)
  - 3 prints of Mike Mitchell (first husband of Milly Bennett); 4 prints of the University of Hawaii; 3 early family prints, Milly Bennett and others; 4 prints of Milly Bennett and others; 19 prints of Milly Bennett and others in Hawaii; 31 prints of scenes in Hawaii; 6 prints of Milly Bennett and others; 2 unidentified prints, circa 1920 (Envelope C)
  - 2 prints related to the murder trial of Liu Fook: Liu Fook and others; Liu Fook, Judge Sylvain Lazarus and others, 1930 (Envelope D)
  - 2 prints of Milly Bennett, Randall Gould and others, circa 1918; 1 print of Milly Bennett and others, 1918 (probably in the office of The Daily News); San Francisco, 1918; 37 unidentified prints, 1917-1922 (Envelope E)
  - 6 prints of Milly Bennett; 9 prints of Milly Bennett and others; 2 unidentified prints, 1917-1922 (Envelope F)
  - 1 print of Stephanie Dolgorouky (autographed), 1927 (Envelope G)
  - 1 print of Eugene Chen; 1 print of Mme. Sun Yat-sen (Soong Ching-ling); 1 print of Michael Borodin and Yu Yu-jen; 1 print of General Fa-Kwei; 2 prints of Rayna Prohme, 1 print of Milly Bennett, Rayna Prohme, William Prohme and others in Hankow, China, 1927; 1 print of Henry H.Y. Hsu and Harold C. A. Ra (?); 2 unidentified prints of China, 1927 (Envelope H)
  - 1 print of William Prohme (Envelope I)
  - 1 print of Hsu Chien, Sun of, Tang Yen-kai, Feng Yu-hsiang, Yu Yu-jen, Wang Ching-wei, Tang Shen-chi, General Galen (Vasily K. Blucher) Chengchow; 1 print of Tang Shen-chi,Yu Yu-jen, Feng Yu-hsiang, Chengchow, China, 1927 June (Envelope J)
  - 2 prints of Earl Browder and Tom Mann in China, 1927; 1 print of Tom Mann; 4 prints of Milly Bennett in China; 6 prints of Milly Bennett and Wilbur Burton (?); 6 prints of Milly Bennett and others, China, 1927; 1 print of Wilbur Burton (?); 2 prints of Randall Gould and others, China, 1927; 1 print of Peg Vaughn and others, China; 18 prints of scenes in China, 1926-1927; 1 print of Yolande and Sylvia Chen; 1 print of Percy Chen (children of Eugene Chen); 1 print of Vincent (Jimmy) Sheean (?), 1927; 3 prints of wall posters, Hankow, China, March 1927; 2 prints of Milly Bennett, Anna Louise Strong and others; 1 print of Milly Bennett and others; 2 scenes of the Chung Yang Dyke Project, China, circa 1927; 1 print of Milly Bennett; 17 prints taken in Hankow, China on May 19 and May 30, 1927; 1 print of Li Li-san; 4 unidentified prints of China (Envelope K)
  - 3 prints of Milly Bennett, 1929; 1 print of Milly Bennett and others; 37 prints taken on Milly Bennett's trip to Central America, Cuba, Colombia, Mexico, August 15-September 17, 1929; 5 prints of Milly Bennett; 11 prints of Milly Bennett and others (Envelope L)
  - 9 prints of Milly Bennett and others, San Francisco, 1928-1929; 1 print of the San Francisco Press Club, 1930 (Envelope M)
  - 12 unidentified prints; 1 unidentified drawing., circa 1929 (Envelope N)
  - 1 print of Harpo Marx; 1 print of the Marx Brothers: Chico (Leonard), Zeppo (Herbert), Harpo (Arthur) and Groucho (Julius), 1933 (Envelope O)
  - 2 prints of Alex Enukidze, Joseph Stalin, and Maxim Gorky; 1 print of Leo Tolstoy; 2 prints of "Kamenev"; 1 print of Lenin, undated (Envelope P)
  - 2 prints of Milly Bennett and others in the Soviet Union, circa 1931; 1 unidentified print; 15 prints of Milly Bennett and others in Moscow, 1931-1936; 4 prints of Evgeni Konstantinov; 1 print of Konstantinov and others; 2 prints of Konstantinov, Milly Bennett and others; 2 unidentified prints; 6 prints of the Children's Theatre, Moscow, circa 1933 (Envelope Q)
  - 9 prints of Pushkina, U.S.S.R.; 1 print of Milly Bennett; 1 print of Milly Bennett and others, 1933; 1 print of Bill Shatov and others; 2 prints of Evgeni Konstantinov; 15 prints of scenes in the Soviet Union; 36 prints of Soviet Lapland, 1932; 1 print of Milly Bennett; 4 unidentified prints (Envelope R)
  - 6 prints of Milly Bennett and others in the Soviet Union; 5 unidentified prints in the Soviet Union; 2 prints of Milly Bennett, Bob and Jenny Miller, 1936; 11 prints of the Moscow Bolshoi Theatre and actors; 1 print of Milly Bennett and others; 1 unidentified print (Envelope S)
  - 10 prints of children's art in Spain, 1937 (Envelope T)
  - 1 print of Hans Amlie, 1938; 1 miscellaneous print; 6 unidentified prints, possibly of migrant camps, circa 1941; 1 print of Hans Amlie, circa 1940; 2 prints of Hans Amlie during the Spanish Civil War, circa 1937; 5 prints belonging to Hans Amlie; 6 prints of Milly Bennett, circa 1940; 10 unidentified prints, circa 1940; 8 negatives; 23 negatives; 1 print of Hans Amlie and others, Pozarubio, Spain, circa 1937 (Envelope U)
  - 63 postcards from the Soviet Union, undated (Envelope V)
  - 14 postcards, Leningrad; 31 postcards, Spain, 1936 (Envelope W)
  - 25 postcards, Paris, circa 1936; 53 postcards, Museum of Modern Western Art, Moscow (Envelope X)
  - 1 print of migrant camp, circa 1941 (Envelope mY)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, 1936-1960 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1960 (Box-folder 21: 1-2)
    Primarily consists of letters (sent and received) between Milly Bennett and Seema Allan.
  - Writings, undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
    Primarily typescript drafts with handwritten annotations and edits.
  - Deathbed notes, 1960 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    Handwritten notes written by Milly Bennett to Seema Allan after she was no longer able to speak.
  - Materials relating to Milly Bennett's will and death, 1960 November (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Writings of Seema R. Allan about Milly Bennett, undated (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Meeting minutes, Ward A-8, 1956 August (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 21: 8)